<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Henry - My blog</title>
    <description>A blog about my journey to developer.</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2017 11:46:52 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 May 2017 11:46:52 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.4.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Resources for JavaScript &amp; jQuery</title>
        <description>&lt;ul class=&quot;list--divided&quot;&gt;
  &lt;h2&gt;Treehouse Resources&lt;/h2&gt;
  
    &lt;li class=&quot;list-item&quot;&gt;
      &lt;div class=&quot;grid__col--12 flex-wrap&quot;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;grid__col--4 no-padding&quot;&gt;
          &lt;a href=&quot;https://teamtreehouse.com/library/javascript-basics&quot; class=&quot;treeh-panel&quot;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&quot;treeh-panel-heading text-center centered&quot; style=&quot;width:90%&quot;&gt;
              JavaScript Basics
            &lt;/div&gt;
          &lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;grid__col--8&quot;&gt;
          &lt;h3&gt;JavaScript Basics&lt;/h3&gt;
          &lt;p&gt;JavaScript is a programming language that drives the web: from front-end user interface design, to backend server-side programming, you'll find JavaScript at every stage of a web site and web application. In this course, you'll learn the fundamental programming concepts and syntax of the JavaScript programming language.&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;span&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;https://teamtreehouse.com/library/javascript-basics&quot; class=&quot;btn btn__hover&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;View Course&lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  
    &lt;li class=&quot;list-item&quot;&gt;
      &lt;div class=&quot;grid__col--12 flex-wrap&quot;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;grid__col--4 no-padding&quot;&gt;
          &lt;a href=&quot;https://teamtreehouse.com/library/jquery-basics&quot; class=&quot;treeh-panel&quot;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&quot;treeh-panel-heading text-center centered&quot; style=&quot;width:90%&quot;&gt;
              jQuery Basics
            &lt;/div&gt;
          &lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;grid__col--8&quot;&gt;
          &lt;h3&gt;jQuery Basics&lt;/h3&gt;
          &lt;p&gt;jQuery Basics covers why you'd want to use jQuery, what it is and how to include it in your projects. You'll build several projects over the course to give you the confidence to integrate jQuery in your own projects and add that level of flair and interactivity to any site you work on.&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;span&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;https://teamtreehouse.com/library/jquery-basics&quot; class=&quot;btn btn__hover&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;View Course&lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  
    &lt;li class=&quot;list-item&quot;&gt;
      &lt;div class=&quot;grid__col--12 flex-wrap&quot;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;grid__col--4 no-padding&quot;&gt;
          &lt;a href=&quot;https://teamtreehouse.com/library/ajax-basics&quot; class=&quot;treeh-panel&quot;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&quot;treeh-panel-heading text-center centered&quot; style=&quot;width:90%&quot;&gt;
              AJAX Basics
            &lt;/div&gt;
          &lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;grid__col--8&quot;&gt;
          &lt;h3&gt;AJAX Basics&lt;/h3&gt;
          &lt;p&gt;AJAX is an important front-end web technology that lets JavaScript communicate with a web server. It lets you load new content without leaving the current page, creating a better, faster experience for your web site's visitors. In this course, you'll learn how AJAX works and how you can use JavaScript to communicate with a web server.&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;span&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;https://teamtreehouse.com/library/ajax-basics&quot; class=&quot;btn btn__hover&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;View Course&lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;JavaScript Tutorials&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;grid__col-flex&quot;&gt;
  
    &lt;div class=&quot;grid__flex-1 grid__col-flex &quot;&gt;
      &lt;a href=&quot;http://eloquentjavascript.net/&quot; class=&quot;book-panel&quot;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;book-panel-heading text-center centered&quot; style=&quot;width:90%&quot;&gt;
          Eloquent JavaScript
        &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;This is a book about JavaScript, programming, and the wonders of the digital. You can read it online here, or get your own paperback copy of the book.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;a href=&quot;http://eloquentjavascript.net/&quot; class=&quot;btn btn__hover flex-margin-top btn-inline-table &quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;View Book&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  
    &lt;div class=&quot;grid__flex-1 grid__col-flex &quot;&gt;
      &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.codecademy.com/learn/javascript&quot; class=&quot;book-panel&quot;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;book-panel-heading text-center centered&quot; style=&quot;width:90%&quot;&gt;
          Introduction To JavaScript
        &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Learn the fundamentals of JavaScript, the programming language of the Web.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.codecademy.com/learn/javascript&quot; class=&quot;btn btn__hover flex-margin-top btn-inline-table &quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;View Course&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  
    &lt;div class=&quot;grid__flex-1 grid__col-flex &quot;&gt;
      &lt;a href=&quot;http://jsforcats.com/&quot; class=&quot;book-panel&quot;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;book-panel-heading text-center centered&quot; style=&quot;width:90%&quot;&gt;
          JavaScript For Cats
        &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;JavaScript is a programming language or, in other words, a means by which a computer is instructed to do things.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;a href=&quot;http://jsforcats.com/&quot; class=&quot;btn btn__hover flex-margin-top btn-inline-table &quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;View Book&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  
    &lt;div class=&quot;grid__flex-1 grid__col-flex &quot;&gt;
      &lt;a href=&quot;https://egghead.io/courses/learn-es6-ecmascript-2015?utm_source=drip&amp;amp;utm_medium=email&amp;amp;utm_campaign=learn-es6&quot; class=&quot;book-panel&quot;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;book-panel-heading text-center centered&quot; style=&quot;width:90%&quot;&gt;
          Learn ES6 (ECMAScript 2015)
        &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;This course takes a look at some of the new features that JavaScript has available with ES6 (ECMAScript 2015). It is a &quot;montage&quot; from several instructors.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;a href=&quot;https://egghead.io/courses/learn-es6-ecmascript-2015?utm_source=drip&amp;amp;utm_medium=email&amp;amp;utm_campaign=learn-es6&quot; class=&quot;btn btn__hover flex-margin-top btn-inline-table &quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;View Course&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jul 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/resources-for-javascript</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/resources-for-javascript</guid>
        
        
        <category>javascript jquery Wyncode</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>My path to Developer &amp; Bootcamp</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;At the beginning of 2015, I was at Miami Dade College getting my AA in Computer Science and working full time for Advance Auto Part as an Assistant Manager, to be able to pay for my tuition. It got to the point, that I didn’t know what to do by the time because, yea!!, MDC was teaching me a lot of the concept of programming and theories, which I actually like, but I wasn’t actually coding anything. So, in mid May, 2015, decided to take a break from college, and start teaching myself HTML5 and CSS3 at &lt;a href=&quot;https://teamtreehouse.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Teamtreehouse&lt;/a&gt;. A few month pass… and I was loving what I was learning at treehouse. One day, I started doing some research and came across with Bootcamp that where not to pricey compare to college and teach how to become a developer  with the latest technology in a period of nine to twelve weeks. Base on the research they seem legit, so I told myself, this is the opportunity that I been waiting for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;choosing-the-right-bootcamp&quot;&gt;Choosing the right Bootcamp&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was late July, 2015, which I apply to different Bootcamps such as &lt;a href=&quot;http://devmountain.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;DevMountain&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://wyncode.co&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;Wyncode&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://ironhack.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Iron Hack&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://bloc.io&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Bloc&lt;/a&gt; they all accepted me. I was really happy and totally leaning toward DevMountain because of their free housing and their campus look extraordinary. Iron hack I went to their location but it wasn’t my style and  Bloc is similar of treehouse but I want it to be around developers. Last, Wyncode I went to their location and the environment they have is amazing and their staff as well. So, here I was deciding between DevMounatin and Wyncode, what led me not to go to DevMountain was that I had to move and I wasn’t ready for that. Wyncode sound better for me, located here in Miami, great location and the opportunity to come home everyday sound great! I was super excited to join Wyncode on September 23. Beside that, Wyncode for the first time was having a scholarship program courtesy of &lt;a href=&quot;http://knightfoundation.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Knight Foundation&lt;/a&gt;. I apply and better I was award with the scholarship to attend Wyncode, this for me was one of the greatest opportunity I have ever had. I want to thanks Knight Foundation , Wyncode , the three person interviewed me &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/brianbrackeen&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Brian Brckeen(Kairos.com CEO)&lt;/a&gt; , &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/widnystlouis&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Widny St. Louis(Wyncode Alumni)&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/kiesha-moodie-13478315&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Kiesha Moodie (Director of Alumni Engagement for Teach For America)&lt;/a&gt; and especially &lt;a href=&quot;http://knightfoundation.org/staff/matt-haggman/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Matt Haggman&lt;/a&gt; the Program Director/Miami at Knight Foundation for such opportunity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;** &lt;a href=&quot;http://miamiherald.typepad.com/the-starting-gate/2015/09/wyncode-knight-name-future-leaders-of-tech-scholarship-winners-.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Wyncode, Knight Scholarship Winners&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
** &lt;a href=&quot;http://knightfoundation.org/blogs/knightblog/2015/10/15/wyncode-scholarships-help-diverse-students-pursue-careers-tech/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Wyncode Scholarships help diverse students pursue careers in tec&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;my-journey-at-wyncode&quot;&gt;My Journey at Wyncode&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;my-overall-experience&quot;&gt;My Overall Experience:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First of all, attending &lt;strong&gt;WYNCODE&lt;/strong&gt; was one of the best decisions I have ever made. I knew the basic of HTML5 and just a little CSS3 when I started. Since week one, I had to work hard because I was learning something new everyday. It was intensive, but I told myself I must dedicated and commit to it, because is going to sky the limit on what I can learn and archive because this is going to be a life long learning path! There hasn’t been a day since I started that I haven’t go to bed around 2am and waking up around 8am the next day, to keep learning. What I realize is that the best students and developers are the one that puts the extra hours and putting the effort on solving the problems at any circumstance. I really love been surrounded by those kinda people because is motivated me and push me even more to learn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;staff--teachers&quot;&gt;STAFF &amp;amp; Teachers:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The staff at Wyncode is phenomenon, I loved their style of teaching in which they teach a several concepts a day and then put you to practice on building small project and homeworks. Some are hard and make you like quitting but it just take pushing through the stress and overcoming the hard moments because at the end is all rewarding. The lead instructor &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/eddroid&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Ed Toro&lt;/a&gt; is a great teacher, he is very calm and love to teach and see the students learn, as well as the assistant teachers they are really good programmers. I really love the opportunity of been able to learn from top quality programmers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;curriculum&quot;&gt;CURRICULUM:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wyncode curriculum is amazing, like I mentioned it was base on learning new concepts and putting them into practice by small projects and homeworks on a daily basis. On the weekends there were bigger project, that consist of what we have been taught through out the week. The projects are relevant to what most of the top industry are programming in todays world. Last but not least, Wyncode have a great curriculum to become a Ruby on Rails Full-Stack Web Developer as well as a Front End Developer that is what I actually like.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/my-path-to-developer-and-bootcamp</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/my-path-to-developer-and-bootcamp</guid>
        
        
        <category>miamiTech aboutme Wyncode KnightFoundation</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
